So I hope you've just enjoyed yourself experimenting with different LMS locally on your box using the
올라마의 파워를 이용해 다양한 LMS를 실험해보면서 즐거우셨길
power of Olama.
바라요
You've probably had similar experience to me, which is.
여러분도 저와 비슷한 경험을 했을 거예요
I certainly found that Quinn 2.5 is perhaps the most powerful model when it comes to grasp of different
퀸 2를 찾았어요 5는 다른 언어를 이해하는 데 있어서 가장 강력한 모델일
languages.
거예요
Some of the other models are better, I think, at explaining.
다른 모델들은 설명을 더 잘하더군요
So I'd be very interested to hear your observations.
여러분의 의견을 듣고 싶어요
Please do post them with the course or message me direct.
강의랑 같이 post로 보내거나 저한테 직접 보내주세요.
I'd love to hear what you've discovered and this kind of experimenting with different models and and
뭘 발견했는지 듣고 싶어요 다양한 모델로 실험하면서 본인
finding the one that works best for your your problem.
문제에 가장 잘 맞는 걸 찾는 것도요
That is a critical skill for an LM engineer.
달 착륙선 엔지니어에겐 중요한 기술이죠
So this was valuable time spent.
귀중한 시간을 보냈어요
All right.
좋아요
Let's talk about the next eight weeks.
앞으로 8주 동안의 일을 얘기해 보죠
So I am looking to take you from where you are today, over on the left to being a master of LM engineering
그래서 저는 지금 이 자리에서 8주 안에 LM 엔지니어링의 달인이 되게 해드리고
in eight weeks time.
싶어요
And this is how we'll do it.
이렇게 하는 거예요
We'll start this week by looking at models at the frontier of what's possible today, which people call
이번 주에는 현대 기술의 한계를 시험하는 모델들을 살펴볼
frontier models.
거예요
Things like GPT 4001 preview and Claude 3.5, and a number of other pioneering models that are closed
GPT 4001 프리뷰나 클로드 3 같은 거요 5개와 다른 선구적인 모델도 많이 있습니다 비공개 소스로 놀라운
source and are able to achieve amazing things.
걸 성취할 수 있는 모델이죠
And we'll do that through the web user interface like ChatGPT, and also then through the APIs.
챗GPT 같은 웹 사용자 인터페이스를 통해 작업하고 API를 통해서도 하죠
And we're going to build a commercial project, something immediately that will be useful, and there'll
상업 프로젝트를 만들 거예요 당장 유용한 거죠 흥미로운
be an interesting commercial exercise for you as well.
상업 활동도 준비돼 있고요
Then next week we will slap a user interface on top of it using a platform which I love, which is called
다음 주에는 사용자 인터페이스를 그 위에 덧붙일 겁니다 제가 좋아하는 플랫폼을 사용해서요 그래디오라는
Gradio.
거죠
And we will have good fun with it and you'll see that I love it.
정말 재미있을 거예요 제가 좋아하는 걸 알게 될 거예요
I go on about it a bit, but it's so easy to use and it's so easy for people like me who are terrible
제가 좀 떠들긴 했지만 사용하기 정말 쉬워요 저처럼 프런트 엔드에 서툰 사람들이
at front end to build a nice, sharp user interface very quickly indeed.
멋지고 날카로운 사용자 인터페이스를 아주 빨리 빌드하기 정말 쉽죠
We'll do it to solve a classic JNI use case, which is the building an AI assistant, a chatbot, and
JNI의 전형적인 사용 사례를 해결하기 위해 할 겁니다 인공지능 비서, 챗봇을 만드는 거요 하지만
we'll but we'll do so in a way that has audio and pictures.
오디오와 영상이 있는 방식으로 할 거예요
So it's multimodal and it will be able to use tools, which means that it's able to call out to code
멀티모달이고 도구를 사용할 수 있어요 컴퓨터에서 실행되는 코드를 호출할 수 있다는 뜻이죠
running on your computer, which sounds kind of spooky, but it's going to make sense when we do it.
좀 오싹하게 들리지만 우리가 하면 말이 돼요
So that is all.
그게 다예요
Week two.
2주 차예요
In week three, we turn to open source, and we use the ubiquitous Hugging Face platform, which is
3주 차에는 오픈 소스로 넘어갑니다 포옹형 얼굴 플랫폼을 어디에나 사용할 수 있습니다 데이터
used by data scientists and LM engineers across the board and will use it to build both.
과학자와 LM 엔지니어들이 전반에 걸쳐 사용하고 둘 다 구축할 때 사용하죠
We'll use the simple API in hugging face called the pipelines API, and then we'll use the more advanced
얼굴을 안는 간단한 API 파이프라인 API를 사용하고 좀 더 고급 API를
API, and we'll explore things like Tokenizers and models in Hugging Face.
사용합니다 얼굴을 안는 토큰라이저와 모델도 탐색하고요
In week four, we're going to talk about something which is a particularly thorny issue in the world
4주 차에는 인공지능 분야에서 특히 골치 아픈 문제를 다룰
of AI, which is there are so many models to choose from.
겁니다 선택할 모델이 너무 많다는 거죠
How do you go about selecting what is the right model for the task you have at hand?
주어진 작업에 적합한 모델을 어떻게 선택하나요?
So we'll we'll work on things like benchmarks and leaderboards and figure out how do you go about that
벤치마크나 leaderboard 같은 걸 작업해 결정 경로를 어떻게 할지
decision path.
알아내는 거죠
And then we're going to take on a particularly different kind of commercial problem about generating
그리고 특히 다른 종류의 상업적 문제를 다룰 겁니다 코드 생성이죠
We're going to build an application which is able to rewrite Python code as C plus plus high performance
파이썬 코드를 다시 쓸 수 있는 응용 프로그램을 만들겠습니다 C++ 고성능 C++
C plus plus code.
코드로요
And we're going to then try it out with a bunch of closed source and open source models.
비공개 소스와 오픈 소스 모델로 시도해 볼게요
And one of them will be the winner.
그중 한 명이 우승자가 되겠죠
The one that's the winner is going to take our test Python code.
파이썬 테스트 코드를 가져가는 것이 승자가 되는 것이죠
It's going to rewrite it and the new code is going to run 60,000 times faster, which is shocking.
다시 쓸 거예요 새 코드는 60,000배 더 빨리 실행되죠 충격적이에요
And you will see that yourself.
직접 보시게 될 거예요
And then there'll be some exercises for you to build other kinds of code generation tools.
다른 종류의 코드 생성 도구를 만드는 연습도 할 거예요
In week five, we will turn to one of the the topics that is super hot at the moment, which is rag
5주 차에는 현재 아주 핫한 주제 중 하나로 넘어갈 겁니다 쓰레기 회수,
retrieval, augmented generation, using, uh, data stores of information to add expertise to your
증강 세대 정보 저장소를 이용해 전문 지식을 더하는 거죠 LLM은 자체 쓰레기
LLM will be building our own Rag pipeline for answering questions that pertain to an organization.
파이프라인을 구축해 조직과 관련된 질문에 답할 거예요
And then there'll be a difficult commercial challenge for you and exercise in which you apply this to
상업적으로 어려운 과제를 수행할 때 자신의 정보에
your own information.
적용해야 해요
And I'm really excited to see what people make of this, and to see some of your projects of rebuilding
사람들이 어떻게 생각할지 정말 기대되네요 직접 만든 랙 파이프라인을
a Rag pipeline for yourself.
어떻게 재건할지도요
In week six, we begin our three week flagship project for this course.
6주 차에는 이 과정의 3주 간판 프로젝트를 시작하죠
Uh, week six, we will set up the business problem.
6주 차에는 사업 문제를 다룰 거예요
We'll do a lot of work on data, and we're then going to create some traditional machine learning models,
데이터 작업을 많이 할 겁니다 그런 다음 전통적인 머신 러닝 모델을 만들 거예요 기준선을
which is very important to do to build a baseline.
구축하는 게 아주 중요하죠
And then we'll try models at the frontier, and we'll fine tune models at the frontier as well, to
거기서 모델을 만들어 보고 사업상 문제를 해결하기
do as well as we possibly can with this business problem.
위해 최대한 노력할 거예요
In week seven, we'll apply it to open source.
7주째에는 오픈 소스에 적용할 거예요
We're going to take open source models and they're initially going to perform terribly, and we're going
오픈 소스 모델을 도입할 겁니다 처음에는 성능이 형편없었지만 미세
to make it our mission to improve those open source models by fine tuning until at least we can compete
조정으로 오픈 소스 모델을 개선하는 것이 우리의 임무입니다 GPT 4와 경쟁할 수
with GPT four.
있을 때까지요
The model at the frontier.
개척지의 모델이죠
And I'm not going to tell you what happens, but I will tell you that I believe that the results will
결과는 말씀 못 드리지만 이 말은 해드릴 수 있어요 그 결과가 여러분을 놀라게
astonish you.
할 거예요
I will tell you that.
그건 확실해요
So it is very much worth hanging on and seeing what happens in week seven.
7주 차에 어떻게 될지 지켜보는 게 좋겠어요
But then it all comes together in the finale in week eight, which is a fitting conclusion to the eight
하지만 8주 차 최종회에서 모든 게 맞아떨어져요 8주 동안 완전한
weeks we are going to build a fully autonomous Agentic AI solution, which will have seven agents collaborating
자율형 인공지능 해결책을 개발할 겁니다 7명의 요원이 협력해서 진짜 상업적 문제를
to solve a real commercial problem.
해결할 거예요
And the end.
끝이죠
Not only will it be doing something where it scans the internet for various things, but will end up
인터넷에서 다양한 걸 스캔할 뿐 아니라 푸시 알림도
sending you push notifications with some of its discoveries.
보내죠 발견되는 것들과 함께요
So it's going to be really fabulous.
정말 멋질 거예요
It's going to have a terrific result at the end of it.
결국 멋진 결과가 나올 거예요
It will be a good way to to be a culmination of everything that you've learned each week, building
매주 배운 모든 것의 정점이 될 수 있는 좋은 기회예요 지난주 배운
on top of it, of the of the prior week, and resulting in true commercial projects that you'll be able
걸 바탕으로 해서 당장 본업에서 실행할 수 있는 진정한 상업 프로젝트가
to put into action in your day job right away.
탄생하는 거죠 Put